JOSÉ CARLOS ROMÁN RUBIO

Software engineer

Website: https://josecarlosroman.com/ / Latest CV can be downloaded at: https://github.com/jcdotnet/curriculum

BACKGROUND

2014

Ingeniería técnica en Informática de Sistemas (3-year university degree focused on Computer Engineering, Information Technology and Software Engineering). Final grade: NOTABLE. FYP defended on 13th of March and marked as SOBRESALIENTE. University of Málaga.

EXPERTISE

(amnutar scianca i	years of experience	۱
Compater science	Vedia of experience	,

'		'			
Programming languages		Microsoft		Java	
C#	>5year	Desktop (Windows Forms)	>3year	Data Access / JDBC	<1year
Java	<1year	Desktop (WPF)	>2year	Java GUI	<1year
HTML, CSS	>5year	ASP.NET	>1year	Java EE	<1year
JavaScript	>6year	ASP.NET MVC	<1year	Spring	<1year
TypeScript	<2year	SOAP WS (asmx)	>3year	Apache Tomcat	<1year
PHP	>5year	SOAP WS (WCF)	<1year	Hibernate	<1year
C/C++	<1year	REST WS (Web API)	<1year	Apache Maven	<1year
Python	<1year	SSRS, SSAS	<1year		
Objective C	<1year	Entity Framework ORM	<1year		
Swift	<1year	XNA, Unity	<1year		
Web		JavaScript		PHP	
HTTP protocol	>4year	jQuery	>6year	Composer	<1year
REST API	>1year	Node.js, NPM	<1year	Laravel	>2year
Apache HTTP server	>4year	Express	<1year	Symfony	<1year
AWS (s3, cloudfront)	<1year	Angular	<1year	WordPress	>4year
Firebase	<1year	React	>1year	WooCommerce	<2year
SASS	<2year	Vue	<1year	Prestashop	<1year
Bootstrap	>2year	Ionic Framework	<1year	Joomla!	<1year
Foundation	<1year	NativeScript	<1year	Drupal	<1year
SEO tecniques	>1year	Mongoose ODM	<1year	Doctrine ORM	<1year
		Grunt, gulp, webpack, etc.	>1year	Eloquent ORM	<1year
Software development		Databases		Other	
Computer programming	>8year	SQL	>6year	Computer architecture	<1year
Android development	<1year	Relational databases	>6year	Operating Systems	<1year
Git	>4year	MySQL	>5year	Linux	<1year
Subversion	>1year	MongoDB	<1year	Computer Networks	<1year

Languages

- Upper-intermediate in written English.

Personal skills

- Organized, critical thinking, good at solving problems, efficient, self-motivated

PROJECTS

2016/01 – 2016/09	Healthcare desktop application. Skills: .NET, WPF, MySQL, Business Intelligence
2012/10 - 2015/03	Sports training software. Skills: .NET, winForms, web services, SQL Server.

EXPERIENCE

2016/01 - present	Software engineer. Self-employed
2014/09 – 2014/11	Programmer at Grupo JyA.
2014/06 – 2014/09	.NET and PHP Programmer at BOLT accelerator.
2008/06 – 2010/01	Owner and manager of a fashion and accessories shop.

COURSES AND CERTIFICATES

2017	Full Stack Web and Multiplatform Mobile App Development. The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology. <u>Verified certificate and courses.</u>
2017	Server-side Development with NodeJS, Express and MongoDB. Verified certificate and grade.
2017	Ionic and Cordova. Verified certificate and grade.
2017	Front-End JavaScript Frameworks: Angular. Verified certificate and grade.
2017	UDEMY: https://www.udemy.com/user/josecarlosromanrubio/
2016	Front-End JavaScript Frameworks: AngularJS. Verified certificate and grade.
2016	MongoDB using the MEAN stack. MongoDB. Self-paced. Grade achieved: 100%.
2015	Web Application Development with JavaScript and MongoDB. University of London. Length: 4 weeks. Grade achieved: 100%
2015	Intro to meteor.js development. University of London. Duración: 4 semanas. Calificación: 92%.
2015	Interactive programming in Python. Rice university. Length: 8 weeks. Grade achieved: 100%
2015	HTML5.2x: Advanced techniques. W3C. Length: 4 weeks. Grade achieved: 86%
2015	Game programming with C#. UCCS. Length: 12 weeks. Grade achieved: 100%
2015	CS188.1x: Artificial Intelligence. UC Berkeley. Length: 12 weeks. Grade achieved: 84%.
2015	Programming Mobile Applications for Android Handheld Systems. University of Maryland. Length: 8 weeks. Grade achieved: 94.8%.
2012	English B1 certificate. EOI Málaga
2007	Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (.NET framework 2.0). Forman. Length: 670 hours.
2006	Desarrollo de aplicaciones J2EE with work experience in Novasoft. Forman. Length: 360 hours. Course outline. Certificate of completion